在这一点上，我想跳到一个真正的网站。
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: At this point,
I wanna jump into a real site.
我想跳进一个工作场所。
I wanna jump into a working site.
所以我们要打开 Honkify 网站。
So we're going to open
up the Honkify site.
并且已经安装在你的,
And that will already
be installed in your,
jason Lengstorf: 这里是代码编辑器，所以
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: Code editor here, so
我们可以把包裹缝起来。
we can just close up the packages.
我们要去 Honkify 工作。
We're gonna be working in Honkify.
所以就看一下吧。
So just take a look at it.
它有一个 index.mdx，所以它已经在使用 mdx 了。
It's got an index.mdx, so
it's already using mdx.
让我们启动它，然后看一下，好吗？
And let's just boot it up and
take a look, yeah?
为此，我们开发了纱线工作空间
So we do yarn workspace honkify develop
杰森 · 兰斯托夫: 好吧，那么
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: Okay, so
我们的图书馆有一个营销页面。
we've got a marketing page for
our library.
这是一个非常重要，非常有用的 JavaScript 库，我鼓励使用它
This is a very important, very useful
JavaScript library that I would encourage
你们所有人今天都要安装。
all of you to install today.
当你打开它的时候,
What it does is when you turn it on,
它会确保你的浏览器按喇叭而不是跟随链接。
it will make sure that your browser
honks instead of following links.
我想添加文档到这个网站。
I wanna add documentation to this site.
所以我建了一个图书馆。
So I've built a library.
我有一个主页。
I've got a homepage.
每个人都喜欢它，每个人都想使用它，但是我们还没有添加文档。
Everybody loves it, everybody wants to
use it, but we haven't added docs yet.
所以我不想从头开始重新设计医生。
So I don't wanna have to
reinvent docs from scratch.
我想安装一个主题。
I wanna install a theme.
所以我能做的就是安装这个主题。
So what I can do is I can
just install this theme.
所以我们要停止服务器。
So we're going to stop the server.
我将使用
And I will install the theme using
纱线工作空间。
yarn workspace honkify add.
因为我们要安装一个本地主题所以我要加上引号,
And then because we're installing a local
theme, I'm gonna put it in quotes,
“ gatsby-theme-docs@* ”。
"gatsby-theme-docs@*".
杰森 · 兰斯托夫: 好的，一切都很好。
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: Okay, all good.
然后我将在我的 gatsby 配置中配置它。
Then I'm going to actually
configure it in my gatsby config.
为了做到这一点，我要下去
And so to do that,
I'm just gonna go down and
我们将把它放在盖茨比插件主题 UI 的正上方。
we'll stick it right above
gatsby plugin theme UI.
秩序在这里不重要。
Order shouldn't matter here.
我没有测试它。
I didn't test it.
我不会冒险的。
And I'm not gonna tempt fate.
所以让我们把它放在我上次放的地方。
So let's put it where I put it last time.
我们要把它安装在这里。
We're going to install it here.
这次我们要在主题上设置一些选项，因为我们已经
We're going to set some options on
the theme this time because we already
有个主页，对吗？
have a homepage, right?
所以我们希望我们的文档生存在斜杠文档中，而不是像站点的根目录那样。
So we want our docs to live at slash docs,
not at like the root of the site.
所以我要设置一个文档的基本路径。
So I'm gonna set a base path of docs.
我要处理一个前导斜杠。
And I'm gonna deal with
with a leading slash there.
因为我们已经安装了 MDX,
And then because we already
have MDX installed,
我想说我确实想使用外部 MDX。
I'm gonna say that I do
wanna use external MDX.
一旦安装完成，我能做的就是让我们看看。
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: And once that is
installed, what I can do is let's see.
杰森 · 兰斯托夫: 让我们启动它，看看效果如何。
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: Let's just
start it up and see how it goes.
为此，开发纱线工作空间。
So yarn workspace honkify develop.
在这里，我们已经有了。
And in honkify, we've already got.
为了避免创建大量文件,
To avoid having to
create a bunch of files,
我只是在这里创建了一些空的文档供我们使用。
I just created some empty docs
files here for us to work with.
好像有什么东西坏了。
And looks like something broke.
杰森 · 兰斯托夫: 我漏了一个逗号。
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: I missed a comma.
Jason Lengstorf: 在逗号到位的情况下再试一次。
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: Try that one
more time with the comma in place.
杰森 · 兰斯托夫: 好的，网站正在运行。
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: Okay,
the site's running.
没有错误。
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: No errors.
杰森 · 兰斯托夫: 好的，所以如果我们来这里看看,
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: Okay, and so
if we come out here and we look,
没有什么明显的改变，但是如果我使用 Docs 会发生什么呢？
nothing is visibly changed, but
what happens if I go to Docs?
我没有创建索引页面。
And I didn't create an index page.
那么让我们来看看文档 / 安装。
So let's go to doc/installation.
好吧，我们的主题是可行的，但不是很正确。
Okay, so our theme works,
but it's not quite right.
它选择了颜色，但是没有选择主题。
It's picking up the colors but
it's not picking up the theme.
所以我们要使用组件阴影来告诉文档主题使用
So we're gonna use component shadowing
to tell the Docs theme to use
Honkify 的布局。
the layout from honkify.
所以让我们跳到这里，在源文件夹,
So let's hop in here and
in the source folder,
我要创建一个新文件，它会存在于盖茨比主题文档中。
I'm going to create a new file and
it's gonna live in gatsby-theme-docs.
一旦我们进入盖茨比主题文档,
And once we go into gatsby-theme-docs,
again,
我们所做的当你的组件跟踪是通过目标这个文件夹,
what we're doing when you're component
shadowing is by targeting this folder,
我们可以访问主题内部的完整源文件夹。
we get access to the full source
folder inside of the theme.
所以我们不包括来源。
So we don't include the source.
我们直接进入里面的东西。
We just go straight into
whatever's in there.
所以我们想知道这些组件。
So we wanna get at the components.
我想改变 layout.js。
And I wanna change layout.js.
现在，当我重启服务器的时候,
So now, what will happen is
when I restart the server,
博士的主题是拿起这个文件。
the docs theme is gonna pick up this file.
所以如果我现在这么做，它会失败，因为它不是一个反应元件。
So if I did it right now, it would fail
because it's not a react component.
所以我要做的代替是我要导入布局从,
So what I'm gonna do instead is
I'm gonna import layout from,
让我们在这棵树上，我要得到组件 / 布局。
let's get up the tree here, and
I'm gonna get components/layout.
然后我要导出默认布局。
And then I'm going to
export default layout.
所以实际上我刚才说的是,
So effectively what I've
just done is I've said, hey,
文档主题，使用这个布局组件。
docs theme,
use this layout component instead.
因此，它将取代我们。
And so it will replace that for us.
所以让我们实现它。
So let's make that happen.
杰森 · 兰斯托夫: 在开始的时候,
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: And
upon getting started up,
当我们刷新页面的时候我们会看到,
what we should see when we
refresh the page is that now,
我们的文档还能用，但是他们从我们的网站上提取了图层。
our docs still work but
they've picked up the layer from our site.
所以不需要对主题本身做任何修改,
So without having to make any
changes to the theme itself,
我们的主题文件现在看起来，像是属于这个网站的。
our theme files now look like
they belong on this site.
当我们移动的时候，它看起来就像是同一个网站的一部分。
And when we move around, it looks
like it's all part of the same site.
这就是我们开始看到盖茨比主题的力量的地方。
So this is where we start to
see the power of gatsby themes.
我们做了，什么八行代码和
We did, what eight lines of code and
我们现在已经在网站上建立了一个功能齐全的文档部分。
we've got a fully functional doc section
on the site now that we built it.
这是一个非常强大的模型，当我们进入它时，它给了我们很大的力量。
That's a really powerful model that gives
us a lot of power when we get into it.
接下来我们要做的是，我想能够使用这个按钮，对吗？
The next thing that we wanna do is I want
to be able to use this button, right?
我们有这个按钮，我想能够使用，在一个活动的可编辑区域。
We've got this button I wanna be able
to use that in a live editable region.
所以我要做的就是创建一个 scope.js
So what I'm gonna do is I'm
going to create a scope.js and
现在我们要覆盖主题内部的 scope.js。
now we're gonna overriding that
scope.js inside of the theme.
我可以导入按钮
And I can import the button
从组件 / 按钮。
from components/button.
然后我要导出默认值。
And then I'm gonna export default.
我只是希望这个按钮是可用的。
And I just want the button
to be available.
Jason Lengstorf: 为了测试这一点，让我们停止并重新启动。
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: And to test this,
let's stop and restart.
我要去看看医生
And I'm gonna go into the docs and
我们加入一个可编辑的块。
let's add in an editable block.
所以我们要设置 jsx，使它的反应-生活和
So we're gonna setup jsx,
make it react-live and
我想导出一个函数。
I want to export a function.
所以我要为它编写一个自定义的点击处理程序。
So I'm gonna write a custom
click handler for it.
这就是我们以前做过的警报。
And that will just be that
alert that we did before.
我们将返回一个片段
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: And
we will return a fragment
有个方向。
that's got a heading.
然后我们将使用我们的按钮。
And then we will use our button.
所以我们没有导入按钮，我们已经把它放在范围内。
So we're not importing the button,
we already put it in the scope.
这意味着我们可以使用它。
That means that we can use it.
所以我要设置一些文本。
So I'm gonna set up some text.
我们的短信会按喇叭的。
Our text is gonna be honk.
而 onClick 将是我们刚才写的句柄点击函数。
And the onClick is going to be our handle
click function that we just wrote.
好吧，假设一切顺利，当我保存这个，回来。
Okay, so, assuming all has gone well,
when I save this, get back out.
我忘了关我的碎片。
I forgot to close my fragment.
但我们可以看到，它为我们捕捉到了这一点。
But we can see here,
it caught that for us.
它告诉我们，我们搞砸了，对不对？
It told us that we screwed it up, right?
所以现在，一旦我关闭这个，回到这里。
So now, once I close this up,
come back out here.
就是这样，好的，所以它发出咔嗒声。
There we go.
Okay, so it clicks.
更有趣的是，如果我们激活 honkify，它就会工作。
And what's even more fun is if we
activate honkify, [SOUND] it works.
它与页面相互作用，对吗？
It interacts with the page, right?
这是一个非常非常好的建立交互式示例的方法
So this is a really, really nice way
to set up interactive examples and
允许人们玩游戏，这样他们就可以实时看到事情是如何工作的，然后进行编辑。
allow people to play so that they can see
how things work in real time and edit.
我认为我们需要做的最后一件事，[声音]哎呀。
And I think the last thing that
we need to do, [SOUND] whoops.
我们只需要给它添加一个链接。
[LAUGH] Is we just need
to add a link to it.
所以如果我们进入我们的页面，我们可以复制这个并且说，阅读文档。
So if we go into our pages, we can just
duplicate this and say, read the docs.
我们直接跳过这个安装过程。
And we'll just skip right
through to that installation.
所以现在在我们的主页上，我们有一个到文档的链接。
So now on our homepage,
we've got a link to the docs.
只用了五到十分钟。
And in what, took like five, ten minutes.
我们只是在一个现有的站点上建立了一个全新的文档部分
We just set up an entirely new doc section
on an existing site that looks like it
属于这个网站。
belongs on this site.
所以我认为这就是你开始看到盖茨比主题的力量的地方
And so I think this is where you start
to see the power of gatsby themes and
为什么有如此强大的抽象概念。
why there's such a powerful abstraction.
因为我们做了所有的痛苦，设置配置和潜水通过
Cuz we did all of that pain of setting
up the config and diving through
定制，并确保 docs 文件夹已经创建。
the GraphQL Schema customization, and
making sure that the docs folders created.
所有这些工作，最终的结果就是我们得到了这样的即插即用的东西。
All that work, and the end result is we
get plug-and-play drop in stuff like this.
当你开始使用相反的主题时，这真的是一个很好的体验
It's really really nice experience when
you start using the theme as opposed to
建造它。
building it.
所以，让我们保存我们的工作。
So let's save our work.
然后，我想看看它的感觉如何创建一个新的网站使用的主题。
And then, I wanna see how it feels to
create a new site using the theme.
我要去哪儿，我们到了。
Where am I going, here we are.
所以我们要做一个 git add all。
So we're gonna do a git add all.
检查状态。
Check the status.
我们得到了修改过的安装说明设置了主题,
And we've got our modified installation
instructions, we set up the theme,
安装主题，隐藏布局和范围，并更新主页。
installed the theme, shadowed the layout
and the scope, and updated the home page.
那么让我们提交 Jason Lengstorf: 好的,
So let's commit
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: Okay,
我们把那个推上去。
let's get that pushed up.